<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Let the Chips Fly</title>
    <link>https://example.com</link>
    <description>The official home of the Let the Chips Fly podcast. High stakes. Big risks. No regrets.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:06:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Decision, Decision, Decision: The Philosophy and Craft of Lee Dukes]]></title>
      <link>https://example.com/episodes/the-first-chip</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://example.com/episodes/the-first-chip</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Join us for a &quot;deep dive&quot; into the life, wisdom, and technical mastery of <strong>Lee Dukes</strong>, the founder of the Charlotte Woodcarvers Club. This episode explores the journey of a man who evolved from helping Boy Scouts carve simple neckerchief slides to becoming a defining figure in the woodcarving community through relentless dedication to his craft.</p><p>We break down the <strong>foundational philosophy</strong> that defined Dukes’ work: a mental discipline he summarized as <strong>&quot;decision, decision, decision&quot;</strong>. This mantra posits that every single cut requires a conscious, decisive action; to hesitate is to be unprepared to carve. Dukes believed that the true difficulty of the craft was not the physical act, but the continuous mental calculation required to avoid mistakes and splintering.</p><p>Listeners will also discover the <strong>technical breakthrough</strong> that fundamentally changed how Dukes approached the human face—the most difficult subject in woodcarving. By abandoning the broad, flat side of a wood block and instead <strong>carving on the corner</strong>, Dukes discovered he could use the block&#39;s natural geometry to pre-establish the depth of the nose, forehead, and brow, ensuring his carvings never looked flat.</p><p>The episode further explores:</p><p>• <strong>The Three Styles of Dukes:</strong> We examine his work in <strong>caricature</strong> (designed to &quot;evoke a laugh&quot;), <strong>realism</strong> (demanding months of painstaking detail), and <strong>stylized carving</strong> (focused on beautiful, smooth lines and the economy of form).</p><p>• <strong>Material and Safety:</strong> Learn why Dukes preferred the &quot;neutrality&quot; of <strong>basswood</strong> and hear the cautionary tale involving a $187 hospital bill that convinced him to always wear a $32 safety glove.</p><p>• <strong>Inspiration and Legacy:</strong> Dukes was humble about his process, often &quot;getting inspiration&quot; and translating 2D ideas from artists like <strong>Norman Rockwell</strong> or editorial cartoonists into 3D works of art.</p><p>• <strong>A Spirit of Generosity:</strong> Discover why this master craftsman <strong>never sold a single piece</strong>, choosing instead to gift his work to friends, mayors, and the church, or donating hundreds of &quot;toys&quot; to support woodcarving clubs.</p><p>Whether you are a seasoned artist or a curious learner, this episode offers a clean and sharp look at what it takes to move from &quot;good&quot; to <strong>&quot;Best of Show&quot;</strong>.</p><p><br></p><p>This podcast was created using AI and the key source of the content was from the <a href="https://youtu.be/63fP8rrJSg8?si=j_O_fH8o--dXR9BB" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferer">Our Founder Lee Dukes video</a> on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@CharlotteWoodcarversClub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferer">Charlotte Woodcarvers YouTube Channel</a>.</p><p></p>]]></description>
      <enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/10d455534/podcast/play/114007462/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2026-0-14%2F416131910-44100-2-c574197837bbc.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Betting High]]></title>
      <link>https://example.com/episodes/betting-high</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://example.com/episodes/betting-high</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[We dive deep into the world of high stakes and big risks. When to hold 'em and when to fold 'em.]]></description>
      <enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/forcedn/example/podcast_ep2.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>